This video is based on the Key Reinstallation Attacks:
Forcing Nonce Reuse in WPA2
on the demonstration how weakness we discovered in WPA2
can be used to attack Android and Linux devices
First, I will use an Android device to connect to our Wi-Fi testnetwork
which now will be the network in present
Notice that the network uses WPA2 encryption
as indicated by the lock symbol
Additionally, on visiting, for example, match.com,
Android would use HTTPS as an extra layer of protection
This is indicated by the green HTTPS lock
and also especially mentioned when viewing the web page info
In other words, all transmitted information is securely protected using both WPA2 and HTTPS
Let's now start the tools that will be used to attack Android and Linux device
First, the following command is used to start a WPA2 attack script
Notice that I include the protected Wi-Fi network that will be attacked
on that will only target one specific device.
The tools starts by searching for the protected Wi-Fi network we will attack
And then we will clone this network on a different channel
This malicious clone of the network enables the attacker to reliably manipulate handshake messages
which is required to abuse the weakness we discovered.
Second, you make sure the victim can access the internet to our malicious network
Additionally, a more step of executing the sslstrip tool
This tool will try to remove the additional HTTPS protection of improperly configured websites
Finally, I am going to use wireshark to capture any data that the client will be transmitting
You're now ready to carry out the attack
So let's go to the smartphone and then connect to the WPA2-protected test network
Once the victim enabled the Wi-Fi
Android will search for the test network
Once that it discover that network, it will try to connect to the real test network, which is not what we want
Fortunately, we can solve this by sending special Wi-Fi frames that command the Android into switching to a different channel
This tricks Android into connecting with the malicious cloned of the network
Essentially, we now have a man in the middle position between the victim and the real Wi-Fi network
This allows us to reliably manipulate the messages
and carry out the key reinstallation attack against the 4-way handshake
Normally, after executing such an attack
the victim will reuse nonces when encrypting data frames
and this allows us to recover any encrypted data
However, due to the implementation bug
Android and Linux will not reinstall the actual secret key
Instead, they will reinstall an all-zero encryption key
This makes a trial to intercept and
manipulate all data that is transmitted by these devices
When we now go to Wireshark, we can already see that a significant amount of data was intercepted
Note that normally all these data encrypted using WPA2 and therefore isn't readable by the attacker.
However, without knowing the password of this protected wifi network
we can read all the packets that the victim is sending
This clearly demonstrates that we have successfully bypass WPA2
Let's now visit a website on the Android device of the victim
And particular, you will again visit the match.com
As you can now see, there is no longer a green HTTPS lock on the address bar of the browser
This means the website is no longer using HTTPS as an additional layer of protection
Note that you're able to bypass HTTPS using sslstrip tool
although this matter of bypassing HTTPS does not working in proper configured websites
it does work against a significance fraction
Unfortunately, many users do not realize HTTPS is no longer used
and therefore will continue to login using their real e-mail address and password
The attacker is now able to intercept the e-mail address and password of the victim.
Of course, this is only a demonstration using a fake account
meaning the login fails
Nevertheless, the attacker is able to see which password we try to use
So let's go to the attacker and search for the login attempt
We can see that the attacker was indeed able to intercept the username and password that the victim used
To avoid being a victim of this attack against WPA2, you must update all your Wi-Fi devices